viking-direct.co.uk 2019-12-04

# Privacy & Security | Viking Direct UK

### 1 Welcome

This document sets out our Privacy Notice in relation to our processing and use of customer data. In this policy you and your refer to the person, data relating to whom we may process from time to time, being our customer or any representative of our customer, or being a visitor to our website.

### 2 General

Office Depot is a group of companies with the European headquarters in Venlo, the Netherlands, and is the data controller for the purposes of the General Data Protection Regulation. For further information visit http://eur-lex.europa.eu/.  
This Privacy Notice explains how we handle the collection, processing, use, and disclosure of your personal data (personal data means any information relating to an identified or identifiable natural person).

At Office Depot, the next fundamental principles related to personal data are followed:

  * We are thoughtful about the personal information we ask you to provide and the personal information that we collect about you.
  * We store personal information for only as long as we have a reason to keep it.
  * We aim to make it as simple as possible for you to control what information.
  * We aim for full transparency on how we collect, use, and share your personal information.

### 3 What information do we collect about you? *¹

In order to fulfill the requests of site users, you may be requested to provide some or all of the following information:

  * Your name
  * Your E-mail address
  * Your mailing/postal address
  * Your delivery address
  * Your telephone number
  * Your contact details.

*¹ Any additional (sensitive) personal information collected under the Introducer Appointed Representative agreement is directly collected and processed at the Insurance Factory Ltd site and not by Office Depot. We invite you to visit the Insurance Factory Ltd privacy policy which you can access via https://www.insurancefactory.co.uk/privacy-policy.  
Viking Direct Insurance Services is a trading name of Office Depot International (UK) Ltd, an Introducer Appointed Representative of Insurance Factory Ltd which is authorised and regulated by the Financial Conduct Authority (No. 306164)

### 4 Where Office Depot collect such information?

Office Depot collects personal information when you register with us or place an order. We also collect information e.g. when you voluntarily complete customer surveys, provide feedback and participate in competitions. Website usage information is collected using cookies.  
When registering for the newsletter, your e-mail address and, if applicable, your name will be used for Office Depot own advertising purposes until you unsubscribe from the newsletter. The unregistration is possible at any time.

### 5 How will we use the information about you?

We collect and process information about you only for the indicated purpose(s), including to: 

  * Process your order
  * Manage your account
  * Payment process
  * Deliver products based on your interests
  * Improve the quality of our products and develop new ones
  * Analyse trends
  * Improve of site design and security.

All personal data will be treated confidentially. The personal data collected about you will be processed, used and stored for the purpose of processing and executing your order including credit checks, personalization of the website, marketing activities.  
If necessary, your data will also be transmitted to service partners (e.g. transport service) and processed and used by them only for the consented purpose.Office Depot will not share any of your information with companies outside our group unlawfully.

### 6 Subject Access Request *²

You have the right to request information about your data we process or store. You may ask us to correct or remove information you think is inaccurate at any time. The following link will take you to the subject access request from. http://sar.officedepot.eu

*² Viking Direct Insurance Services access requests are handled directly by the Insurance Factory Ltd and If you have any questions or want to exercise any of your data rights please contact the Data Protection Officer at: Data Protection Officer, Distinct Business Insurance, 45 Westerham Road, Bessels Green, Sevenoaks, Kent, TN13 2QB.

### 7 Cookies and similar technologies

What are Cookies?  
A cookie is a piece of data, a text file with anonymous information that includes a unique user identification and website name. Tracking technologies such as cookies, beacons, tags and scripts may be used for analyzing trends.For further information please be referred to the Cookie Notice. (<https://www.viking-direct.co.uk/cookies>)

### 8 Other websites

This Privacy Notice only applies to this website. Our websites contain links to other websites. So, please note that Office Depot is not responsible and assumes no liability for the content of external websites even if the links refer to them.

### 9 Complaints *³

If Data Subjects have a concern or intend to complain to Office Depot about how their Personal Data has been processed or appeal against any decision, they can reach out to the Data Protection Office by using the email address [DPO@officedepot.eu](mailto:DPO@officedepot.eu) or lodge a complaint with a supervisory authority.

*³ Viking Direct Insurance Services complaints should be raised by telephone on 0121 296 3100.  
Alternatively please write to us at: Customer Experience Team, Viking Direct Insurance Services, Haden House, Unit 16 Waterfall Trading Estate, Waterfall Lane, Cradley Heath, B64 6PU.

### 10 How to contact us

You can contact our Data Protection Officer via:

**Email:** [DPO@officedepot.eu](mailto:DPO@officedepot.eu)

**Or write to us at:**  
DPO  
Office Depot  
Columbusweg 33  
5928LA Venlo  
Netherlands.

This document is amended from time to time.

Venlo, 11 February 2019.
